Guide to the Bristow Adams papers, 1853-1970, 1862-1957 (bulk)
Adams, Bristow papers, 1853-1970
- Series II. Bristow Adams
  - Subseries A. Correspondence, 1880-1970
    Mrs. Ada Gertrude Adams, Ardis Adams, Bristow Benjamin "Tote" Adams II, Edith Adams, Eleanor Adams, Everett Adams, Luella Farmer Adams, Wallace Adams, Walter "Wallie" Adams, Josephine Albrecht, Henry G. Alsberg, "Bebe", Margaret Bourke-White, H. D. Brandyce, Eric Branham, George C. Calvert, Sherwin Cody, Charles Collingwood, Clement V. Conole, Helen C. "Connie" Conrad, Elmer Farmer Creighton, Edmund E. Day, Wallace Duncan, John English, Mrs. Nettie Farmer, B. T. Galloway, A. W. Gibson, David Greenberg, Reed Harris, Charles Heffernan, Lester W. Herzog, E. B. Jansen, David Starr Jordan, Russell Lord, Deane W. Malott, Albert R. Mann, Constance Adams Means, Tom Means, Wallace Miller, Florence Morton, Everett Opie, Gifford Pinchot, "Queenie", Mrs. Alexis Romanoff, Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., Theodore Roosevelt, Sr., Elihu Root, Harold M. Schmeck, Jr., Jacob Gould Schurman, Everett Smith, Ada Adams Stone, Walter King Stone, Tom Storey, William Howard Taft, Charles S. Thompson, Robert E. Treman, Gertrude Adams Turner, Henry Brown "Tony" Turner IV, Peter Vischer, E. B. "Andy" White, Lee A. White
    - 1880 - Dec. 1895 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Jan. - Dec. 1896 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Jan. - Mar. 1897 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Apr. - May 1897 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - June 1897 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - July - Sept. 1897 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Oct. 1897 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Nov. - Dec. 1897 and ca. 1897 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Jan. 1898 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Feb. 1898 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Mar. 1898 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Apr. 1898 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - May 1898 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - June 1-15, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - June 20-31, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - July 1898 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Aug. 1898 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Sept. 1898 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Oct. 1898 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Nov. 1898 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook of letters from Bristow Adams to his family, Aug. 1896 - Apr. 1897 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Dec. 1898 and ca. 1898 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Jan. 1899 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Feb. 1899 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Mar. - Apr. 1899 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - May 1899 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - June 1899 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - July 1899 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Aug. - Sept. 1899 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Oct. - Nov. 1899 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Dec. 1-15, 1899 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Dec. 19-31, 1899 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - ca. 1899 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 1900 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Feb. - Apr. 1900 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - May - June 18, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - June 25-31, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - July 1-10, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - July 11-14, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - July 15-20, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - July 21-31, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Aug. 1-7, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Aug. 16-31, 1900 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1900 and ca. 1900 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Jan. - May 1901 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - June 1-12, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - June 13-30, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - July 1-4, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - July 5-10, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - July 11-16, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - July 17-21, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - July 22-25, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - July 26-27, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - July 28-30, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Aug. 1-4, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Aug. 5-10, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Aug. 11-22, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Aug. 23-31, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Sept. 1-14, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sept. 15-22, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Sept. 23-30, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Oct. 1-7, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Oct. 8-14, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Oct. 17-29, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Nov. 1-12, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Nov. 13-26, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Dec. 1-13, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Dec. 15-22, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Dec. 29-30, 1901 and ca. 1901 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Jan. 1-9, 1902 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Jan. 12-20, 1902 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Jan. 23-30, 1902 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Feb. 1-7, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Feb. 8-23, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Mar. 2-3, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Mar. 4-6, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Mar. 7-16, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Mar. 17-24, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Mar. 28-31, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Apr. 2-7, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Apr. 8-29, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - May - Dec. 1902 and ca. 1902 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Jan. - June 1903 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - July - Aug. 1903 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1903 and ca. 1903 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Jan. - July 10, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - July 11-21, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - July 22-27, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Aug. 1-14, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Aug. 16-29, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1904 and ca. 1904 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Jan. - Feb. 1905 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Mar. - June 1905 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Jul-05 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Aug. - Dec. 1905 and ca. 1905 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1906 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Jul-05 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Aug. - Dec. 1905 and ca. 1905 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1906 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - May - Dec. 1906 and ca. 1906 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1908 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - May - Dec. 1908 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1909 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Jan. - June 1910 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - July - Dec. 1910 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Jan. 1911 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Feb. 1-9, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Feb. 10-26, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Mar. 1-8, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Mar. 12-28, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Apr. 1-11, 1911 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Apr. 13-17, 1911 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Apr. 18-30, 1911 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - May 1911 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - June 1911 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - July 1911 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Aug. - Dec. 1911 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - ca. 1911 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Jan. - Aug. 1912 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Sept. 1912 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Oct. - Nov. 1912 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Dec. 1912 and ca. 1912 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Jan. - Sept. 1913 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Oct. - Dec. 1913 and ca. 1913 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1913 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - May - June 1914 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - July 1914 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Aug. - Sept. 1914 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Oct. 1914 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Nov. 1914 - Dec. 22, 1914 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Dec. 24, 1914 and ca. 1914 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Jan. - Feb. 1915 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Mar. 1915 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Apr. - June 1915 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - July - Dec. 1915 and ca. 1915 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Jan. - July 1916 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Aug. - Sept. 1916 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Oct. - Dec. 1916 and ca. 1916 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Jan. - May 1917 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - June - July 1917 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Aug. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Sept. - Oct. 7, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Oct. 9 - Dec. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - ca. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Jan. 1918 - June 1918 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - July 1918 - Aug. 1918 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Sept. - Nov. 11, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Nov. 12 - Dec. 1918 and ca. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - 1919 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Jan. - June 1920 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - July - Dec. 1920 and ca. 1920 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1921 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - May - Dec. 1921 and ca. 1921 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Jan. - June 1922 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Jul-22 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Aug. 1922 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1922 and ca. 1922 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Jan. - June 1923 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - July - Dec. 1923 and ca. 1923 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Jan. - Aug. 1924 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1924 and ca. 1924 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Jan. - Mar. 1925 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Apr. - June 1925 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - July - Dec. 1925 and ca. 1925 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Jan. - June 1926 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - July - Dec. 1926 and ca. 1926 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Jan. - May 1927 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - June - Dec. 1927 and ca. 1927 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - 1928 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 1929 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Jan. - Feb. 1930 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Mar. 1930 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Apr. - May 1930 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - June - Aug. 1930 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Oct. - Dec. 1930 and ca. 1930 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - 1931 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - 1932 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - 1933 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - 1934 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - 1935 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Jan. - Feb. 1936 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Mar. 1936 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Apr. 1936 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - May 1-8, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - May 9-30, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Jun-36 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - July - Dec. 1936 and ca. 1936 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Jan. - Aug. 18, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Aug. 26, 1937 - Dec. 1937 and ca. 1937 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Jan. - Sept. 1938 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Oct. - Dec. 1938 and ca. 1938 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - 1939 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - ca. 1939 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - 1940 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - 1941 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - 1942 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Jan. - June 1943 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - July - Dec. 1943 and ca. 1943 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Jan. - July 1944 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Aug. - Dec. 1944 and ca. 1944 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - 1945 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - 1946 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1947 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - May - Dec. 1947 and ca. 1947 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Jan. - Mar. 1948 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Apr. - July 1948 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Aug. - Dec. 1948 and ca. 1948 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Jan. - June 1949 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - July - Dec. 1949 and ca. 1949 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Jan. - June 7, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - June 9 - Oct. 1950 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Nov. 1-22, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Nov. 24-30, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Dec. 1-9, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Dec. 10-20, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Dec. 21-29, 1950 and ca. 1950 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - ca. 1950 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - ca. 1950 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Jan. - Feb. 1951 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Mar. - June 1951 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - July - Nov. 1951 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Dec. 1951 and ca. 1951 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Jan. - Feb. 9, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Feb. 18, 1952 - Apr. 30, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - May - Aug. 1952 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Sept. - Nov. 1952 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Dec. 1952 and ca. 1952 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Jan. - June 1953 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - July - Nov. 1953 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Dec. 1953 and ca. 1953 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Jan. - Mar. 1954 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Apr. - May 1954 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - June - July 1954 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Aug. - Dec. 1954 and ca. 1954 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Jan. - May 1954 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - June - Aug. 1955 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Sept. - Nov. 1955 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Dec. 1955 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - ca. 1955 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - ca. 1955 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Jan. - May 1956 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - June - July 1956 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Aug. - Nov. 1956 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Dec. 1956 and ca. 1956 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 1957 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Feb. 1957 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Mar. 1957 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Apr. - June 1957 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - July - Oct. 1957 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Nov. 1-20, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Nov. 21-30, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Dec. 1-18, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Dec. 19-30, and ca. 1957 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Jan. 1958 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Feb. - Aug. 1958 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1958 and ca. 1958 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - 1960, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - 1962-1965 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - 1966-1970 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - n.d. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - n.d. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - n.d. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - n.d. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - n.d. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - n.d. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - n.d. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - n.d. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - n.d. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - n.d. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - n.d. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - n.d. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B. Radio Talks
    Between 1940 and 1956 Bristow gave many, talks, usually about 10 minutes in length, over radio station WGY in Schenectady. These included: "Farm Paper of the Air," part of the Cornell Agricultural Extension program; "Let's Read a Book," a monthly series; "The World and Us," based upon his experiences on two trips around the world in 1930 and 1930-39; and a series of recollections and anecdotes of his experiences as a child growing up in Washington, D.C. and VA aired during the last programs.
    - 1. Miscellaneous
      - "Farm Paper of the Air," ca. 1940-1949, and "Farm Forum" (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Book Review, ca. 1950-1956 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - 2. "The World and Us"
      - 1936, Jan. 1946 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - May - Oct. 1946 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Nov. 1946 - May 1947 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - June 1947 - Dec. 1947 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Jan. - July 1948 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Aug. 1948 - Apr. 1949 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - May - Oct. 1949 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Nov. 1949 - Apr. 1950 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - May 1950 - Oct. 1950 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Nov. 1950 - Nov. 1951 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Dec. 1951 - July 1952 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Aug. 1952 - Apr. 1953 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - May 1953 - Oct. 1953 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Nov. 1953 - Apr. 1954 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - May 1954 - Sept. 1954 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Oct. 1954 - Jan. 1955 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Feb. 1955 - May 1955 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Sub-series C. "Recollections"
      - June - Nov. 1955 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Nov. 1955 - May 1956 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - June 1956 - Oct. 1956 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Nov. - Dec. 1956 and May 1954 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Subseries C. Articles, published and unpublished
    Adams wrote on many subjects from homemaking, forestry, journalism and sports to education. Many were published in various newspapers and magazines.
    - Homemaking and Food (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Sports and Art (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - National Forests, Farms and Gardens (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Forestry (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Forestry (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Forestry (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Wildlife and "Personal Attitude Toward Life" (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Publicity (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - W.P.A. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Savage Club, Press Club, Sigma Delta Chi (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Cornell (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - W.W. I and Peace (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Town problems: traffic and government (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Publicity (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Publicity (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D. Speeches
    Bristow gave speeches in his professional capacities as professor, journalist, and forester on topics similar to those he wrote about.
    - W.W. II (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Education and Cornell (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Conservation (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Publicity (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Athletics (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Journalism (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Journalism (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Subseries E. Creative Writing
    Contains poems, short stories, plays and jokes.
    - Poetry and jokes (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Poetry and jokes (Box 36, Folder 1-7)
    - Plays, including "Driven Back to Egypt" (Box 36, Folder 8-11)
    - Short Stories (Box 36, Folder 12-13)
    - Short Stories (Box 37, Folder 1-4)
  - Subseries F. Biographical Material
    Contains several papers lauding the achievement of Bristow Adams, clippings from "Who's Who" and attempts at an autobiography.
    - Eulogies, tributes, genealogy (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Biographical material (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Resume of Stanford experience (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Biographical material (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Subseries G. College Material
    Includes illustrated class notes and early papers form Stanford, exams and lecture notes for his Cornell courses in journalism and conservation, and memorabilia
    - Stanford class notes and papers (Box 37, Folder 9-13)
    - Stanford class notes, papers and diploma (Box 38, Folder 1-6)
    - Cornell course material (Box 38, Folder 7-14)
    - Cornell course material (Box 39, Folder 1-4)
    - Memorabilia: Medals, name badges, Quill and Dagger Invitations, letter opener (Box 39, Folder 5-7)
  - Subseries H. Financial Records
    Contains miscellaneous financial records from the Adams household.
    - Cash book (1911), C. R. Morrison account book check stubs (1902-1906) (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Expense book (1924) (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Cash Book (1916) and check stubs (1947-1949) (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Check books (1951-1953, 1953-1955) (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Subseries I. Publications
    Bristow Adams was either founder editor or faculty advisor for most of these publication. In college he was co-founder and editor of the "Pathfinder" in 1892; editor-in-chief of the "Stanford Sequoia"; associate editor of the daily newspaper; and founder and editor of the Stanford humor magazine, "The Chaparral." From 1902-4 he edited "Forestry and Irrigation," forerunner of "American Forests," and was co-founder and managing editor of a weekly news review, "Washington Life" from 1903-5. "Washington Life" was later renamed the "American Spectator," and Adams remained editor until 1906. Bristow did illustrations for "Country Life in America;." "Everybody's," "World's Work," "Overland," and "Pacific Monthly." He gained experience in forestry as an assistant in charge of technical and literary revision of publications of the U.S. Forest Service. In 1921 he wrote "An Agricultural Almanac," Farmer's bulletin 1202 for the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture.
    At Cornell Bristow directed and edited the Cornell Agricultural Extension Publications. He was also a member of the board of directors of "The Cornell Daily Sun," unofficial advisor to "The Cornell Countryman," and faculty advisor to "The Delicate Brown" and "The Cornell Widow." He also founded, in 1952, "The Cornell Plantations," and remained its editor until his death in 1956.
    - Cornell Forester, 1920-1921 (Box 40)
    - Cornell Alumni News, 1917-1957 (Box 40)
    - Forestry and Irrigation, 1903 (Box 40)
    - The Delicate Brown, 1920-1950 (Box 40)
    - The American Spectator, 1906 (Box 41)
    - American Forests, 1934-1935, 1958 (Box 41)
    - American Forestry, 1914, 1917-1918 (Box 41)
    - The Pathfinder, 1913, 17 and 41 (Box 41)
    - The Cornell Countryman, 1916-1919 (Box 42)
    - The Cornell Plantations, 1944-1962 (Box 42)
    - The Cornell Widow (Box 42)
    - The Chaparral, 1956 (Box 42)
    - The Stanford Sequoia, 1898-1899 (Box 42)
    - The Ace, 1920, 1946 (Box 42)
    - Cornell Era, 1919-1920 (Box 42)
    - The Cornell calendar (1917) (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous publications (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous publications (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous publications (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous publications (Box 45)
    - Miscellaneous publications (see also Box 58) (Box 46)
  - Subseries J. Art Work
    Includes early sketches and water colors, magazine covers from the early 1900's,and seal drawings
    - Eighteen Ivy League athletic posters drawn by Adams (Folder 1)
    - "Twenty Crayolas by Bristow Adams, France 1924" Prints, watercolors, lettering (Box 47)
    - Seal drawings, notebooks, broadsides, bookplate watercolors, magazine covers (Box 48)
    - Sketches from pre-high school and high school years and a portrait of Bristow by Dorothy Witt Thomas (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - [Crawford Cadawallader Adams, Correspondence and Military Papers:] Receipts and Expenses from Masonic Temple, n.d.; Certificate of Ada Gertrude Adams as wife of C. C. Adams 32nd degree, Master of the Royal Secret of the Scottish Rite of Freemasons, Southern Jurisdiction (see also Series III, Subseries A) (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Subseries K. Photographs
    Contains photographs taken during Bristow's work in the forest service, various forest service and of friends and family
    - Album of track team in England in 1924 (Box 50)
    - Trips around the world - 1930. Track meet in England, ca. 1926, forestry (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Forestry (Box 50, Folder 2-8)
    - Forestry (Box 51, Folder 1-3)
    - Friends, family, misc. 1878-1955 (Box 51, Folder 4-9)
    - Friends, family, misc., 1878-1955 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - World trips, ca. 1930 (Box 52, Folder 2-8)
    - World trips ca. 1930, 2 portraits of Bristow (Box 53, Folder 1-6)
    - Negatives, 2 printing blocks, boxes of slides (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Series L. Scrapbooks and clippings
    Scrapbooks contain clippings of articles by Bristow or on subjects of interest to him, including one on "The Milkshow Publicity," 1909
    - Clippings by or of interest to Bristow, 1932-1939 (Box 54)
    - 1908-1917, 1917-1922, 1922-1926 (Box 55)
    - 1919-1931, 1906-1956 (Box 56)
    - 1923-1924 (Box 57)
    - [See Subseries I. Publications] The Pathfinder, Bound Vols. I and II (Box 58)
    - Clippings, 1917-1941, 1941-1955 (Box 59)
    - Milkshow publicity Apr. 1919 (see also Box 65) (Box 60)
  - Subseries M. Miscellany
    - 21st Anniversary Booklet of Farm Broadcasting at WGY (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - 3 Phonograph records of Bristow Adams on Farm Forum, 2/22/52 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Address book n.d. (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - "World's tour journal" n.d. (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Forest service notebook Sept. 3, 1912-Oct. 3, 1912 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Subscriptions for the Cornell Plantations n.d. (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Date book for 1915 with expenses noted (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Copy of "On the Choice of a Profession by Robert Louis Stevenson, given to Adams by his friend Fred W. Dewart (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - "Rude Rural Rhymes" by Bob Adams (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - The Society of American Foresters certificate of Bristow Adams becoming a senior member. Jan. 1915 (Box 61, Folder 10)
- Series III. Crawford Cadwallader Adams
  - Subseries A. Correspondence and Military Papers
    Consists primarily of business correspondence exchanged between C. C. Adams and various officials during the Civil War. Also included is a scrapbook containing excerpts from personal letters. (See also Box 49, Folder 2, p. 29)
    - 1853 - Mar. 1862 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Apr. - Nov. 1862 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - 1863 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Jan. - Feb. 1864 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Mar. - May 4, 1864 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - May 5-30, 1864 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - June 1864 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - July-Nov. 1864 and ca. 1864 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - 1866 - 1869 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - 1870 - 1875 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - 1876 - 1881 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - 1882 - 1897 and n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence n.d. Autobiographical material Civil War medal Map of Washington, D.C. (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook of excerpts of letters exchanged between C. C. Adams and Ada G. Harrison Adams 1871-1885 (Box 64)
    - [See II. Bristow Adams, Subseries L. Scrapbooks and clippings, p. 30] Clippings, 1921-1946. (Box 65)
- Series IV. Miscellaneous
  - College athletic posters, 1900's (Folder 1)
  - Sketches and artwork, Undated (Folder 2)